for today's video I want to talk about a
thought experiment so imagine our world
consists of two islands one island is
based purely on competition survival of
the fittest
profit the highest God the other island
is based on cooperation people get to
choose which island they live on and
they also can to change that choice at
any time products can flow freely
between the the islands and so can ideas
in a world like that what ends up
happening what is the working conditions
on both islands look like what would
make people move from one island to
another what products are better and
cheaper and faster depending on which
spot there is another piece to this
experiment I like to add is that these
islands shrink and grow with the number
of people that are on them so if you
choose to move to competition island you
get to take your footprint of a world
with you and so the island shrinking
grow as as the people choose to live
there I think sitting with this thought
experiment that the working conditions
would become very similar that is you
could there would be no need for minimum
wage even on competition Island because
you would have to pay people enough to
entice them to not be in cooperation
Islands cooperation Island mimics
socialism one of the critiques of
socialism is this idea that we would all
starve to death under it and if that's
the case well he just moved to
competition Island now who cares about a
thought experiment except this thought
experiment it's very similar to what
we're actually creating with the global
cooperative we don't have two islands we
have the Internet and we have
corporations when we start a global tech
cooperative and invite people we're
starting cooperation Islands the only
way we bring people in is if it's
voluntary if it entices them if the
products and services we are creating
are better cheaper faster than what is
on the
other side and we keep improving working
conditions and improving what we offer
to the point where it not only affects
our members but it draws other people
and it affects the competitive world as
well the competitive world can't pay the
weed they don't need a minimum wage once
everyone's needs are met you can't pay
people slave labor wages and expect them
to keep working
so I'm sitting with this thought
experiment over the next few days and
seeing what it is that we can create
together because I think this is also a
good analogy this and the puzzle one I
introduced a few days ago is a great
analogy for the puzzle pieces what's in
it for the individual and this idea of
these two islands one on competition I
wanted cooperation and people being able
to voluntarily choose which one they're
associated with is what we are creating
this world with the global tech
cooperative please like and subscribe
see you on Monday